<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tyler Korthal</title><link>https://tjkorthal.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Tyler Korthal</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 11:41:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tjkorthal.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Project ideas</title><link>https://tjkorthal.github.io/notes/project-ideas/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 11:41:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://tjkorthal.github.io/notes/project-ideas/</guid><description>In progress Dev blog
Keep track of things I&amp;rsquo;ve learned, tried, or want to try
Backlog Go/Node API
Build an API from the ground up, implementing as many features as possible that would be beneficial/expected in a production-ready public API.
I want to do everything from scratch where it makes sense so I can learn more about that feature. I don&amp;rsquo;t feel the need to write my own logger since that doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem like something that would ever come up in the future; it&amp;rsquo;s just writing messages to a file.</description></item><item><title>July 29, 2021 devlog</title><link>https://tjkorthal.github.io/posts/2021-07-29/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 11:20:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://tjkorthal.github.io/posts/2021-07-29/</guid><description>Started working on Node API using Express Took a cursory look into MongoDB and Prisma (Node ORM) Explored using Insomnia to generate documentation and test my API A fresh start Though I know enough JavaScript to get by, I&amp;rsquo;m much more familiar with Ruby. I already have my toolbox of go-to gems for Ruby projects, eg Rails, ActiveRecord, HTTP, RSpec, etc, but my JS toolbox is pretty empty. I&amp;rsquo;ve used Express on small side projects before, and a quick internet search confirmed it&amp;rsquo;s still a reliable JS server framework, but that&amp;rsquo;s about it.</description></item><item><title>July 28, 2021 devlog</title><link>https://tjkorthal.github.io/posts/2021-07-28/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 22:33:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://tjkorthal.github.io/posts/2021-07-28/</guid><description>Got my Hugo blog site working with Github Pages Learned about Github Actions Published coding challenge project from a previous interview TIL Github Actions are workflows, processes, and CI steps baked into the Github ecosystem. You can utilize them by adding config files to a .github/workflows directory in your project, and the configured jobs will run when the specified actions happen (push to a specific branch, a PR is created, etc).</description></item><item><title>So Good They Can't Ignore You</title><link>https://tjkorthal.github.io/posts/so-good-they-cant-ignore-you/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 21:21:39 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://tjkorthal.github.io/posts/so-good-they-cant-ignore-you/</guid><description>After a less-than-successful attempt to find a new job I turned to a friend for advice. He directed me to the book So Good They Can&amp;rsquo;t Ignore You by Cal Newport, and I read through the whole thing in a weekend. It changed my perspective from a &amp;ldquo;passion mindset&amp;rdquo; (what can the world offer me as I pursue my passion of software development?) to a &amp;ldquo;craftsman mindset&amp;rdquo; (what can I offer the world as I become a more valuable software developer?</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://tjkorthal.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 20:23:13 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://tjkorthal.github.io/about/</guid><description>Tyler is a software developer in Fort Wayne, Indiana with over five and a half years of experience in web application development.
Likes:
Ruby 💎 solving problems with code well-defined goals Star Wars hiking cycling techno music Dislikes:
workplace drama tech debt bad or missing documentation being told &amp;ldquo;but we&amp;rsquo;ve always done it this way&amp;rdquo; waking up early</description></item></channel></rss>