<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>devlog on Tyler Korthal</title><link>https://tjkorthal.github.io/tags/devlog/</link><description>Recent content in devlog on Tyler Korthal</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 11:40:19 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tjkorthal.github.io/tags/devlog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>August 5, 2021 devlog</title><link>https://tjkorthal.github.io/posts/2021-08-05/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 11:40:19 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://tjkorthal.github.io/posts/2021-08-05/</guid><description>Started working on a menu API in Node yesterday Wrote a script to sync database records Keeping it simple A few days ago I spun up a simple Node server with Express, started looking into packages to take the place of ActiveRecord, and began learning about MongoDB and how to use it. This was overwhelming, and I stopped because it seemed like too much all at once (spoiler alert: it was).</description></item><item><title>August 2, 2021 devlog</title><link>https://tjkorthal.github.io/posts/2021-08-01/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 13:37:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://tjkorthal.github.io/posts/2021-08-01/</guid><description>More Docker fun! Dockerizing Ruby API at work
I was running into issues with Bundler building native extensions for one of the gems required in the API&amp;rsquo;s Gemfile, but it turned out that the gem was never used within the app. I removed the gem from the Gemfile and was able to successfully install the rest.
Added favicon to blog
TIL Once I got the API Docker image built I ran it in a new container, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t access the API server.</description></item><item><title>July 30, 2021 devlog</title><link>https://tjkorthal.github.io/posts/2021-07-30/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 13:30:58 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://tjkorthal.github.io/posts/2021-07-30/</guid><description>Worked on Dockerizing a Vue project at work TIL Docker has a lot of command line configs to keep track of, but they&amp;rsquo;re really important. These refer to the docker run command:
-p is used to map ports between the Docker container and the host machine. I initially expected the EXPOSE command in the Dockerfile to do this for me, but I learned that mostly just specifies which ports will need mapped.</description></item><item><title>July 29, 2021 devlog</title><link>https://tjkorthal.github.io/posts/2021-07-29/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 11:20:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://tjkorthal.github.io/posts/2021-07-29/</guid><description>Started working on Node API using Express Took a cursory look into MongoDB and Prisma (Node ORM) Explored using Insomnia to generate documentation and test my API A fresh start Though I know enough JavaScript to get by, I&amp;rsquo;m much more familiar with Ruby. I already have my toolbox of go-to gems for Ruby projects, eg Rails, ActiveRecord, HTTP, RSpec, etc, but my JS toolbox is pretty empty. I&amp;rsquo;ve used Express on small side projects before, and a quick internet search confirmed it&amp;rsquo;s still a reliable JS server framework, but that&amp;rsquo;s about it.</description></item><item><title>July 28, 2021 devlog</title><link>https://tjkorthal.github.io/posts/2021-07-28/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 22:33:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://tjkorthal.github.io/posts/2021-07-28/</guid><description>Got my Hugo blog site working with Github Pages Learned about Github Actions Published coding challenge project from a previous interview TIL Github Actions are workflows, processes, and CI steps baked into the Github ecosystem. You can utilize them by adding config files to a .github/workflows directory in your project, and the configured jobs will run when the specified actions happen (push to a specific branch, a PR is created, etc).</description></item></channel></rss>